Guide to the Ivan Collins Papers 1903-1971
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Model research, 1938-1970; Series II:; 1.5 cubic feet.
  - Carriage & Wagon Manufacturers, 1936, 1938, 1956 (Box-folder 1/16)
    Notes, 4 pamphlets, newspaper item, letter, sketches of details, magazine advertisement, 2 magazine items
  - Carriage Manufacturers, undated (Box-folder 1/17)
    Notes, magazine item
  - Carriages, European, 1912 (Box-folder 1/18)
    3 postcards, illustration, newspaper illustration, newspaper items, excerpt from French publication, magazine illustrations, magazine article, notes
  - Carriages, General, 1908-1970 (Box-folder 1/19)
    Letter, 11 newspaper items, 4 magazine items, flyer
  - Chariot (ancient), undated (Box-folder 1/20)
    2 magazine illustrations, newspaper item
  - Circus, 1945-1946, 1970 (Box-folder 1/21)
    Photograph, 6 letters
  - Civil War Cannon, undated (Box-folder 1/22)
    Letter, notes, magazine item, report, 8 newspaper reprints.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-25, and box 10 folder 28.
  - Coach, English, undated (Box-folder 1/23)
    3 magazine illustrations
  - Coaches, State—European, undated (Box-folder 1/24)
    Magazine item, excerpt from French publication
  - Conestoga, 1969 (Box-folder 1/25)
    Booklet, notes, 2 magazine items, 2 letters.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-2, and box 10 folder 22.
  - Cook Wagon, 1965 (Box-folder 1/26)
    2 magazine items, sketches of details, notes, map of Washington state, letter.
  - Cook Wagon, Dufur, 1965 (Box-folder 1/27)
    Sketches of details, newspaper item, notes.
  - Delivery Wagon, Armour's, undated (Box-folder 1/28)
    advertisement/postcard, magazine illustration.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-19.
  - Dougherty Wagon and Ambulance, 1966 (Box-folder 1/29)
    Notes, magazine article, 2 illustrations.
  - Dray, Gooseneck, 1920, 1968 (Box-folder 1/30)
    Notes, 2 letters, receipt, 2 magazine items.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-27, and box 10 folder 12.
  - Drummer's Wagon, undated (Box-folder 1/31)
    Newspaper item, 2 advertisements, 2 magazine items.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-16, and box 11 folder 8.
  - Dump Wagon (mechanical), 1954 (Box-folder 1/32)
    Newspaper photograph, sketches of detail, magazine photograph, letter.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-13, and box 10 folder 26.
  - Excursion Bus, 1970 (Box-folder 1/33)
    Sketches of details, article, letter, 2 magazine illustrations.
  - Escort Wagon, Army, undated (Box-folder 2/1)
    2 newspaper cartoons, 2 magazine articles, notes, sketches of details, magazine photograph, report.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-53, and box 10 folder 5.
  - Furniture Van (Loeser), 1957 (Box-folder 2/2)
    Magazine photograph, letter.
  - Garbage Wagon, undated (Box-folder 2/3)
    Notes, advertisement, sketches of details.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-26.
  - Governess' Cart, undated (Box-folder 2/4)
    Sketches of details, notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-28, and box 10 folder 13.
  - Grain Box, Kent, Oregon, undated (Box-folder 2/5)
    Sketches of details.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-29, and box 10 folder 17.
  - Grain Box, Dufur, undated (Box-folder 2/6)
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-29, and box 11 folder 17.
  - Ice Wagon, undated (Box-folder 2/7)
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-31, and box 11 folder 12.
  - Link Dray, 1970 (Box-folder 2/8)
    2 magazine articles, sketches of details, 5 letters.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-17.
  - Lumber Wagon, undated (Box-folder 2/9)
    3 advertisements, notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-36, and box 10 folder 17.
  - Lumber Wagon, Roll-Off, 1938 (Box-folder 2/10)
    transcripts, sketches of details, 2 letters, pamphlet, notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-34, and box 10 folder 17.
  - McCabe-Powers Body Co., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2/11)
    7 letters, catalog—McCabe-Powers Body Co., article.
  - McKenzie River Stage, 1970 (Box-folder 2/12)
    Advertisement, transcript, notes.
  - Medicine Wagon, undated (Box-folder 2/13)
    2 magazine articles, magazine cartoon, sketches of wagon details.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-55, and box 11 folder 12.
  - Petaluma Cart, undated (Box-folder 2/14)
    Notes
  - Physician's Phaeton, undated (Box-folder 2/15)
    Notes, transparency, gear cards, display title card.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-38, and box 11 folder 13.
  - Pleasure Wagon, 1969 (Box-folder 2/16)
    Sketches of details, paint samples, notes, essay, 3 letters, newspaper item.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-37.
  - Police Patrol Wagon, undated (Box-folder 2/17)
    Magazine photograph.
  - Red River Cart, 1950 (Box-folder 2/18)
    Notes, article, newspaper item, drawing, sketches of details, 2 letters.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-39, and box 10 folder 23.
  - Rockaway, undated (Box-folder 2/19)
    Notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-3, and box 11 folder 22.
  - Sheep and Wool Industry, undated (Box-folder 2/20)
    Notes, 3 essays, article.
  - Sleigh, Bobsled, 1945, 1969 (Box-folder 2/21)
    2 magazine photographs, 2 newspaper items, publication—Pioneer Times, 2 magazine advertisements, magazine article, magazine illustration, 2 letters, sketches of details, notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-46, and box 10 folder 8.
  - Sleigh, Colonial, undated (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Sleigh, Spring, undated (Box-folder 2/23)
    Sketches of details, magazine illustration, magazine advertisement.
  - Sprinkler Wagon, Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 2/24)
    Newspaper item, photograph, price list, magazine article, 17 letters, illustration, description.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-42, box 11 folder 5, and box 2 folder 30.
  - Stage Coach, Road Coach, undated (Box-folder 2/25)
    Note.
  - Surrey Wagon, undated (Box-folder 2/26)
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-41, box 11 folder 25, and box 2 folder 36.
  - Tank Wagon, Oil, undated (Box-folder 2/27)
    Sketches of details, magazine photograph, 2 magazine articles, photograph.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-47, and box 10 folder 6.
  - Wagonette, Hilcrest and Parsons, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2/28)
    12 letters, notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-48, and box 11 folder 6.
  - Wheeled Scraper, 1970 (Box-folder 2/29)
    Transcript, plan of detail.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-43, and box 10 folder 27.
  - Wood Tank, Sprinkler Wagon, 1956 (Box-folder 2/30)
    Captions from exhibit, catalog excerpts, notes, sketches of details, publication—Trolley Talk, photograph.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-42, box 11 folder 5, and box 2 folder 24.
  - Manuscript, Rewrite, undated (Box-folder 2/31)
    Photographs of wagons mounted on cards with descriptions.
  - Yellowstone Coach, 1945 (Box-folder 2/32)
    Newspaper item, notes, letter, magazine article.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-52, and box 11 folder 20.
  - Wool Wagon, undated (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Wagonette or Curtain Omnibus, 1966 (Box-folder 2/34)
    Newspaper item, magazine photographs, 2 newspaper articles, postcard, sketches of details, essay, letter, notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-48, box 11 folder 6, and box 2 folder 28.
  - Victoria, undated (Box-folder 2/35)
    2 newspaper items, notes, caption, photograph, letter.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-65, and box 11 folder 21.
  - Surrey, undated (Box-folder 2/36)
    Magazine photograph, newspaper item, magazine advertisement.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-41, box 10 folder 20, and box 2 folder 26.
  - Stage Coach, Mud Wagon, 1953-1954, 1968 (Box-folder 2/37)
    2 newspaper items, newspaper article, 3 letters, magazine—Junior World, postcard, pamphlet.
  - Stage Coach, Concord, 1942-1958 (Box-folder 3/1)
    Photograph, 2 postcards, 2 newspaper items, telegram, advertisement, speech, 6 letters, 2 reports, 3 magazine articles, illustration, pamphlet, essay.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-1, and box 11 folder 19.
  - Stage Coach, General, 1945 (Box-folder 3/2)
    Newspaper item, 3 newspaper articles, 3 magazine articles, 2 pamphlets, notes, 2 magazine illustrations, report, journal—Historical New Hampshire.
  - Sleigh, Cutter, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    4 newspaper items, magazine illustration, 3 article excerpts, illustration, letter.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-63, and box 10 folder 10.
  - Sleigh, Albany Six Passenger, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 3/4)
    2 newspaper items, notes, sketches of details, 12 letters.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-45, and box 11 folder 1.
  - Sheep Herder Wagon, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3/5)
    2 newspaper items, logos, 2 magazine photographs, advertisement, 2 essays, magazine article, sketches of details, notes, 15 letters, advertisement, photograph.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-44, and box 11 folder 18.
  - Prairie Schooner, 1969 (Box-folder 3/6)
    Notes, magazine advertisement, 5 newspaper articles, magazine photograph, magazine illustration, 2 magazine articles, letter, 2 transcripts.
  - Omnibus, Umatilla, undated (Box-folder 3/7)
    Newspaper item, 2 magazine photographs, 2 magazine illustrations, photograph, essay.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-54, and box 11 folder 23.
  - Mail Wagon, R. F. D., undated (Box-folder 3/8)
    2 newspaper items, newspaper photograph, essay, sketches of mail wagon details, notes, 3 magazine photographs, 2 magazine articles.
  - Mail Wagon, U.S., 1961 (Box-folder 3/9)
    Magazine article, plans.
  - Logging Wagon, undated (Box-folder 3/10)
    3 newspaper items, newspaper article, magazine article, advertisement, magazine illustration, notes.
  - Logging Cart, undated (Box-folder 3/11)
    3 newspaper items, sketches of details, sketch of lumberjack, magazine advertisement, 2 magazine photographs, notes.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-33, and box 10 folder 14
  - Iron-Wheeled Wagon, Thurston (Orchard Wagon), 1965 (Box-folder 3/12)
    Notes, sketches of details, 7 letters, newspaper item, pamphlet.
  - Hearse, 1965 (Box-folder 3/13)
    Notes, newspaper item, sketches of details, receipt, letter, exhibit label.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-51, and box 10 folder 32.
  - Header Box, 1957 (Box-folder 3/14)
    3 newspaper items, receipt, 8 letters, sketches of details, business card.
  - Hansom Cab, undated (Box-folder 3/15)
    Newspaper item, 3 printed photographs, report, sketches of details
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-30, and box 11 folder 25.
  - Granite Lifter (Galamander), undated (Box-folder 3/16)
    Newspaper item, letter.
  - Future Models, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 3/17)
    Newspaper item, notes, 5 letters, magazine illustration, 2 pamphlets, 2 articles, sketches of details.
  - Fuel Wagon, 1969 (Box-folder 3/18)
    3 newspaper items, catalog excerpts, notes, sketches of details, photograph, 2 letters.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-23, and box 10 folder 15.
  - Freight Wagon, Ore., undated (Box-folder 3/19)
    Newspaper item, magazine article, sketches of details, magazine illustration.
  - Fire Apparatus, Ladder Truck, 1942 (Box-folder 3/20)
    Magazine—The Family Circle, 2 magazine articles, magazine photograph, magazine illustration, 3 newspaper items, sketches of details.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-32, and box 11 folder 3.
  - Fire Apparatus, Hose Truck, 1953, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/21)
    7 newspaper items, sketches of details, 4 photographs, notes, 6 letters, receipt, magazine photograph, magazine article.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-24, and box 11 folder 4.
  - Express Wagon, 1969 (Box-folder 3/22)
    Advertisement, newspaper item, notes, sketches of details, letter.
    See also boxes 12 & 13, oversize 2012-20, and box 10 folder 11.
- Topical, 1903-1971; Series III:; 1.5 cubic feet.
  Correspondence with other wagon experts and researchers, interviews, information about creating exhibits and miscellaneous information.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Architecture, undated (Box-folder 4/1)
    2 newspaper items, magazine article.
  - Art Work, undated (Box-folder 4/2)
    Newspaper item, playbill, pamphlet, blank sheet of stationery, 4 magazine illustrations.
  - Bibliography, 1949, 1958 (Box-folder 4/3)
    3 letters, notes, 2 commercial flyers
  - Blacksmithing, undated (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Bjorklund, Lorence, 1966 (Box-folder 4/5)
    4 letters, sketch of gun cart details
  - Brochures, undated (Box-folder 4/6)
    3 receipts
  - Card Scripts, undated (Box-folder 4/7)
    Notes, 6 exhibit title cards, pamphlet
  - Carriages, 1903 (Box-folder 4/8)
    8 newspaper items, 5 carriage prints, almanac, notes, 4 magazine photographs, postcard
  - Chief Crazy Horse Indian Mountain Memorial, undated (Box-folder 4/9)
    Newspaper item, postcard booklet, pamphlet, 5 postcards, informational flyer, copy of South Dakota Historical Society's monthly bulletin
  - Carriage Collections (Stanford, etc.), 1964 (Box-folder 4/10)
    2 letters, 3 published photographs
  - Cases, Display, undated (Box-folder 4/11)
    Promotional flyer, notes, sketch
  - Collection, Dates (Museum of Wagons, U of O), undated (Box-folder 4/12)
    List of items, notes
  - Collections, 1949, 1956, 1963 (Box-folder 4/13)
    2 newspaper items, 5 magazine articles, 2 pamphlets, notes, 5 letters, calendar
  - Collections—Miniature, 1946-1968 (Box-folder 4/14)
    7 newspaper items, 11 magazine articles, pamphlet, 4 letters
  - Construction Procedure Exhibit, undated (Box-folder 4/15)
    18 cards with descriptions and mounted photographs, sketch of express wagon detail
  - Conversion—Carriage to Auto, undated (Box-folder 4/16)
    Newspaper item, notes
  - Personal Items, 1970 (Box-folder 4/17)
    Door plaque, 60 business cards, 2 Carriage Association of America membership cards, mock certificate, letter, magazine article
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 4/18)
    27 letters, newspaper item, sales flyer
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 4/19)
    32 letters
  - Correspondence, 1966, 1967, 1969 (Box-folder 4/20)
    36 letters
  - Correspondence—Museum Announcement, 1965 (Box-folder 4/21)
    10 letters
  - Downing, Paul, undated (Box-folder 4/22)
    14 letters
  - Exhibit Technique, undated (Box-folder 4/23)
    Notes, 4 pamphlets
  - Fences, undated (Box-folder 4/24)
    2 magazine articles, report
  - Freight Map, 1968 (Box-folder 5/1)
    Notes, magazine article, letter
  - Gannon—Reference Material, undated (Box-folder 5/2)
    3 magazine articles, 6 newspaper items, pamphlet and price list, 2 postcards, dissertation abstract
  - Gannon, William L., 1957-1970 (Box-folder 5/3)
    Notes, pamphlet, lists of sale items, business card, photograph, 45 letters, newspaper item
  - Wm. Gannon Thesis Index, undated (Box-folder 5/4)
    Thesis index
  - General, undated (Box-folder 5/5)
    2 postcards, 40 newspaper items, notes, 2 photographs, advertisement, 51 magazine items, letter, dictionary clippings
  - Hall Mark, undated (Box-folder 5/6)
    Sketches, receipt, 2 magazine photographs, photograph
  - Harness Display, undated (Box-folder 5/7)
    Notes, sketches, 2 newspaper items
  - Henderson & Sons, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 5/8)
    5 letters, notes, essay
  - Horses, undated (Box-folder 5/9)
    3 newspaper items, magazine article, pamphlet
  - Human Resources, undated (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Insurance-Appraisal, 1952-1968 (Box-folder 5/11)
    Appraisal lists, notes, 17 letters, insurance policy, memorandum, removal permit, receipt
  - 1969 Interview Letters, undated (Box-folder 5/12)
    Notes, 6 letters, interview transcript
  - Interviews, 1969 (Box-folder 5/13)
    Notes, 2 letters, 4 transcripts
  - Inventory of U of O Collection Items, undated (Box-folder 5/14)
    Inventories
  - Johnson, Dean, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 5/15)
    21 letters
  - Jung Correspondence, 1946-1971 (Box-folder 5/16)
    90 letters, photostat, 3 photographs, 2 newspaper items
  - Jung, Wesley W., 1955-1965 (Box-folder 5/17)
    6 pamphlets, notes, business card, 2 postcards, magazine, 12 newspaper items, 4 negatives (b/w), 33 letters
  - Justification, undated (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Library, undated (Box-folder 6/2)
    4 archival-preservation articles
  - Library (catalogue of books, journals, etc.), 1969 (Box-folder 6/3)
    Bibliographies, envelope, letter
  - Lighting & Electrical, undated (Box-folder 6/4)
    Notes, catalogs
  - Loans & Gifts, 1965-1966, 1970 (Box-folder 6/5)
    Exhibit description card, 5 letters, 3 fruit crate labels, list of gifts
  - Migration—Westward, undated (Box-folder 6/6)
    Magazine article
  - Museum Operation, undated (Box-folder 6/7)
    Product specification for a pump, 2 order lists
  - Newspaper Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 6/8)
    Newspaper advertisement directory
  - Owens, Harry, 1959 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Paint Research and Restoration, undated (Box-folder 6/10)
    Technical leaflet
  - Photo Display Case, undated (Box-folder 6/11)
    Notes, memo
  - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 6/12)
    3 magazine articles, 6 wagon illustrations
  - Pictures, undated (Box-folder 6/13)
    Newspaper item, 2 playing cards, letter, photograph, catalog page, postcard
  - Press, undated (Box-folder 6/14)
    4 newspaper items, 3 pamphlets, magazine article, receipt, guest list, magazine—Newsweek
  - Public Relations, undated (Box-folder 6/15)
    7 technical leaflets
  - 1966 Publications, 1966, 1968 (Box-folder 6/16)
    2 journals, 4 program guides, 2 pamphlets, 2 letters, receipt
  - Publicity, undated (Box-folder 6/17)
    2 press releases, 7 UO news bulletins, label, 6 pamphlets, 10 magazine items, 24 newspaper items
  - Railroad, undated (Box-folder 6/18)
    Catalog, magazine, pamphlet, price list, business card, 10 magazine items, illustration, 14 newspaper items
  - Research Papers, undated (Box-folder 6/19)
    Article
  - River Boats (Sternwheelers), undated (Box-folder 6/20)
    7 newspaper items, notes
  - Schools, 1955, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6/21)
    Narrative, teaching suggestions, school contact list, children's worksheets, notes, 11 letters, map, 2 newspaper items, wagon illustration
  - Scientific American, undated (Box-folder 6/22)
    notes
  - Shaniko, 1965 (Box-folder 6/23)
    Letter, newspaper item
  - Sketch Material, 1944 (Box-folder 6/24)
    Notes, sketches, 13 newspaper items, book cover, menu, flyer, 9 illustrations, 40 magazine items, photograph, booklet
  - Speeches, Briefs, etc., 1969 (Box-folder 7/1)
    Notes, letter, flyer, speeches, collection overview, speech
  - Springs-History—Timken, undated (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Steam Tractors, undated (Box-folder 7/3)
    Notes, magazine article
  - Street Scenes, undated (Box-folder 7/4)
    3 magazine items, printed photograph
  - Supplies, Tools, Materials, undated (Box-folder 7/5)
    Notes, product information pamphlets
  - Studebaker, undated (Box-folder 7/6)
    Catalog excerpts
  - Index to Files, undated (Box-folder 7/7)
    Index
  - Wagon Manuscript Drawings, undated (Box-folder 7/8)
    Sketches of wagon details
  - General Information Series V: Research and Clippings, ca. 1965-1970 (Box-folder 7/9)
    Museum catalog, 3 reports
- Museums and exhibitions, 1946-1971; Series IV:; 1.5 cubic feet.
  Information from various museums which exhibited wagons and notes, logistics, plans and promotion for exhibits of Collins' wagons.
  - State & Local History Association, undated (Box-folder 7/10)
    Questionnaire
  - Suffolk Museum, undated (Box-folder 7/11)
    Catalog
  - Wells Fargo, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 7/12)
    Greeting card, article reprint, postcard, 16 letters, notes, flyer, annual report, magazine, magazine illustration
  - Yakima Museum, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7/13)
    Newspaper item, 6 letters
  - Museums and Wagons (to see), 1953-1956 (Box-folder 7/14)
    Newspaper item, membership form, notes, 14 letters, magazine, 6 museum guides and pamphlets
  - Benefit 1948, undated (Box-folder 7/15)
    Exhibit description card, business card, list of wagons, 2 letters, news flyer, 18 newspaper items
  - Manuscript, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 7/16)
    Typed draft, list of publishers contacted, galley copy, vocabulary test, notes, radio script and announcement, 2 newspaper items, preliminary printed section of book, Trail's End publishing catalog, 23 letters re publishing book, receipt
  - Manuscript—Original Notes, undated (Box-folder 7/17)
    Notebook, loose notes
  - Book Promotion, 1953, 1957 (Box-folder 7/18)
    Press release, 4 pamphlets, envelope, 3 receipts, mailing labels, 11 letters
  - Lettering Styles, undated (Box-folder 8/1)
    Sketches of wagon details, flyer, magazine article, issue of Territorial Enterprise, issue of Virginia City News
  - [Catalog], undated (Box-folder 8/2)
    Para-Tone catalog
  - Meier & Frank Exhibition, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 8/3)
    Railroad ticket, notes, 3 receipts, 3 newspaper items, 27 letters
    See also oversize 2012-60
  - Oregon State Exhibition 1954, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 8/4)
    9 newspaper items, exhibit flyer, notes, calendar, catalog, exhibit plans, 26 letters
    See also oversize 2012-61
  - Auto Show and Exhibitions, 1953 (Box-folder 8/5)
    Exhibition layout, business card, 6 letters
  - Wagon Show 1965, undated (Box-folder 8/6)
    Exhibit layout sketches, magazine, newspaper item, exhibit description card
  - University of Oregon Exhibition 1953, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 8/7)
    Notes, magazine, 4 newspaper items, event schedule, 7 letters
    See also oversize 2012-57
  - University of Oregon Wagon Show 1959, undated (Box-folder 8/8)
    Exhibit layout sketches, logistical information, newspaper item
  - U of O Exhibition 1959, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 8/9)
    Magazine, magazine article, 6 newspaper items, notes, 5 postcards, collection description, 2 receipts, business card, flyer, press release, 11 letters, pamphlet, promotional card
  - Wagon Show 1963, 1959, 1963 (Box-folder 8/10)
    Notes, lecture, 7 magazine items, 3 newspaper items, sketches of display details, plan of exhibit, calendar, 6 letters
  - Television and Radio, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 8/11)
    Notes, newspaper item, 5 television scripts, elementary education guide, 7 letters
  - Threshing Equipment, undated (Box-folder 8/12)
    Notes, printed photograph, 2 magazine items
  - Transportation—Economics, undated (Box-folder 8/13)
    Newspaper items
  - Travel 1970 (Box-folder 8/14)
    2 vouchers, receipt, requisition, 4 pamphlets, letter, notes, essay
  - Travel & Research Trips, 1969 (Box-folder 8/15)
    Airline ticket, notes, letter, travel reimbursement request, 2 travel authorization worksheets
  - Travel Report 1969 (Box-folder 8/16)
    Survey of museums, draft of survey of museums, greeting card, newspaper item, 4 letters
  - University Catalog and Publication, 1966 (Box-folder 8/17)
    Questionnaire, notes, 2 pamphlets, letter
  - University History, 1969 (Box-folder 8/18)
    Legislative mandate, letter, newspaper item
  - Wagons, undated (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Wagon Manufacture Graph, undated (Box-folder 8/20)
    Graph, chart, notes, explanation
  - Wheel, undated (Box-folder 8/21)
    Postcard, notes, book dust cover, definition, newspaper item, magazine item, 3 reports
  - Dr. Willard, 1970 (Box-folder 8/22)
    Filmstrip guide, radio commentary transcript (excerpt), letter, list of Collins' reviews and publications
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1957-1970 (Box-folder 8/23)
    List, 4 pamphlets, 18 letters
  - Chicago Museum of Science and Industry, undated (Box-folder 8/24)
    guide
  - Ford Museum, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9/1)
    2 guides, 3 pamphlets, notes, printed photograph, postcard, 3 letters
  - Oregon Historical Society, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 9/2)